Guide to the Stanford University, Center for African Studies, Records SC0832
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Center for African Studies, records
1963-2005
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Center for African Studies.
SC0832
37.5 Linear Feet 25 Cartons
Information about Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Center for African Studies is an interdisciplinary program for undergraduate and graduate students. CAS at Stanford coordinates with UC Berkeley to form the Stanford/Berkeley Joint Center for African Studies. Through this arrangement courses from each institution are incorporated into one program.
Although there is not an African Studies major at Stanford, the Center for African Studies seeks to specifically acknowledge Stanford students who choose to take our courses, which cover a wide, interdisciplinary range of topics relating to Africa. Both the minor in African Studies and the certificate in African Studies are interdisciplinary programs that allow the participating student the opportunity to select relevant courses in various departments according to his or her interests.
Description of the Collection
Grants files include proposals, budgets, reports, correspondence, memoranda, enrollment statistics, information gathered, and other items.
Conference files include correspondence, notes, programs, brochures, conference papers, and other materials; there are some photographs from the 1993 conference.
African Studies; Stanford University. Center for African Studies.
- Records, Accession ARCH-2006-217
  General note
  Center for African Studies Archival Project
  - Grant files: Title VI, 1976-1987
    - NDEA 1976- 1982 (Box 1)
    - National Resource Center Proposal 1982-83 (Box 1)
    - National Resource Center Proposal and Carryover Funds Report 1983-84 (Box 1)
    - HEA Language Center Joint Proposal (Box 1)
    - Title VI Proposal 1983-84 (Box 1)
    - US DOE Correspondence 1983-84 (Box 1)
    - Title VI Proposal 1984-85 (Box 1)
    - Critical Foreign Language DOE Proposal 1985 (Box 2)
    - Title VI Proposal 1985-86 (Box 2)
    - Title VI Renewal 1986-87 (Box 2)
  - Grant files: Title VI, 1986-1990
    - DOE Grant Correspondence 1986-87 (Box 2)
    - Performance Report 1986-87 (Box 2)
    - Proposal 1987-88 (Box 2)
    - Faculty Questionnaires 1987-88 (Box 2)
    - Three-Year Proposal Materials 1988 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence 1988 (Box 2)
    - Proposal Notebook (Box 2)
    - Performance Report 1988-89 (Box 2)
    - Title VI 1988-91 (Box 3)
    - Title VI Renewal 1989-90 (Box 3)
  - Grant files: Title VI, 1990-1995
    - Title VI Renewal 1990-91 (Box 3)
    - Title VI Proposal 1990 (Box 3)
    - Three-Year Proposal 1991-94 (Box 3)
    - Title VI 1992-93 (Box 3)
    - Budget Revisions 1993 (Box 3)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes 1993 (Box 3)
    - DOE Memos 1993-94 (Box 4)
    - Title VI 1994-95 (Box 4)
    - UC Berkeley Subcontracts 1994-95 (Box 4)
    - Performance Report 1994-95 (Box 4)
    - NRC and FLAS Proposal 1994-95 (Box 4)
  - Grant files: Title VI, 1995-2002
    - Title VI and Budget Revisions 1994-95 (Box 4)
    - Proposal 1995-97 (Box 4)
    - UC Berkeley Subcontracts 1995-96 (Box 4)
    - Title VI 1995-97 (Box 4)
    - UC Berkeley Subcontracts 1996-97 (Box 4)
    - CVs and Misc 1996 (Box 4)
    - DOE Proposal 1997-00 (Box 4)
    - Final Report 1997-00 (Box 4)
    - Performance Report 1999-00 (Box 5)
    - DOE Proposal 1999 (Box 5)
    - Title VI Proposal and Materials 2000-03 (Box 5)
    - EELIAS April 2001 (Box 5)
    - Title VI Proposal, Materials, Data 2002 (Box 5)
  - Conferences:
    - Joint Center Conference – Stanford, April 26, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference – Berkeley, May 2, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference – "Perspectives in African Social History" Stanford, April 10, 1982 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference – Berkeley, April 23, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference April 14, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference Proposed Papers 1985 (Box 5)
    - African Studies Conference May 11, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference May 3, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference "Africa and the World" 1987 (Box 5)
    - Literature Conference February 26-27, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference "The Crisis in Southern Africa" 1988 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference "Conflict and Conflict Resolution" 1989 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference "Reassessing Colonialism in Africa" 1990 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference "African Identities" 1991 (Box 5)
    - Photos from 1993 Conference (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference "Perspectives on African Culture" 1994 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference "Wither Africa: Second Liberation or Sustained Subordination? Economic, Political, Cultural, and Social Perspectives" 1995 (Box 5)
    - Joint Center Conference "Wither Africa: Second Liberation or Sustained Subordination? Economic, Political, Cultural, and Social Perspectives" 1995 (Box 6)
    - "Imagining Home: Culture and Politics of Diaspora" 1995 (Box 6)
    - Joint Center Conference "Migration in Africa: Political Traffic Across Environment and Culture" 1996 (Box 6)
    - Conference Correspondence and Papers 1996 (Box 6)
    - Joint Center Conference "Identities in Africa: Cultures, Politics, Changes" 1997 (Box 6)
    - Graduate Student Conference "Gender, Race, Geography" 1997 (Box 6)
    - Joint Center Conference "Southern Africa in Comparative Perspective" April 25, 1998 (Box 6)
    - Joint Center Conference "Health and Society in Africa" 1999 (Box 6)
    - Joint Center Conference "Human Rights and the Environment in Africa" April 24, 2000 (Box 6)
    - Joint Center Conference "Democracy in Africa" April 28, 2001 (Box 6)
    - Joint Center Conference on Popular Culture, April 26, 2003 (Box 6)
  - CAS Minutes, Memos, and Agendas:
    - March 1963 through 1985/86 (Box 6)
    - 1986/87 through 1999/2000 (Box 7)
    - 2000-2005 (Box 8)
  - CAS Minutes; CAS Administration; Joint Center Materials; Faculty Publications; Campus Newsletters and Publications:
    - CAS Minutes, Memos & Agendas, January 1996 through June 2005 (Box 8)
    - CAS Administration 1964-1998:
      - Committee Notes '64-65, Membership '66-72, Open House 1968, History, CAS Admin 1992-93, Exec/Staffing 1993, Outreach Coordinator Salary 1993, Speakers/Lecturers '93-94, CAS/OMB Workshop 1998 (Box 8)
    - Joint Center Materials 1983-98:
      - Joint Center Newsletters ‘83-94, Joint Center Evaluation '85, Joint Center Mini-Fellowships '85-86, Review of Joint Center '86, Joint Center Council '87, Joint Center Activities ‘88-89, Joint Center Workplan '89-90, Workplan '92-93, Evaluation '93-94, Joint Center Materials '94, Proposal Meeting '94, Joint Center Budget '95-97, Proposal Meeting '97-98 (Box 8)
    - Faculty Publications:
      - David Abernethy, Larry Diamond, Marcel Fafchamps, William Gould, Jonathan Jansen, Scott Pearson, David Rozkuszka (Box 8)
    - Campus Newsletters and Publications Involving CAS, 1979-1998:
      - African Studies Newsletters 1979 & 1983-86, News Clippings about CAS 1983-96, Campus Publicity 1985-86 & 1995-96, Stanford Daily 1993-94, Campus Report 1994-95, African Studies Newsletters 1994-98 (Box 8)
  - ASA/SPICE:
    - ASA October 14-18, 1980, Philadelphia (Box 8)
    - ASA November 1985, New Orleans (Box 8)
    - ASA Outreach Committee 1986-1987 (Box 8)
    - ASA News April/June 1987 (Box 8)
    - ASA Women's Caucus Mentor File 1993-1994 (Box 8)
    - Ramphele Visit, November 1996 (Box 8)
    - ASA November 1996 (Box 8)
    - SPICE Outreach: Francophone Africa Project (Box 8)
    - SPICE General 1980-1981 (Box 8)
    - SPICE General 1981-1982 (Box 8)
    - SPICE Articles 1982 and other (Box 8)
    - SPICE Receipts 1983-1986 (Box 8)
    - SPICE 1985 Curriculum Guidelines for Summer Institute (Box 8)
    - SPICE Correspondence 1985-1985 (Box 8)
    - SPICE Film and Video Tape Collection 1986 (Box 8)
    - SPICE Lesson Content Checklist 1986 (Box 8)
    - SPICE Office Memos 1986 (Box 8)
    - SPICE Staff Meetings 1986-1987 (Box 8)
    - SPICE Publications 1986-1987 (Box 8)
    - SPICE Purchase Orders 1987 (Box 8)
    - SPICE Curriculum Materials Evaluation Checklist 1987 (Box 8)
    - SPICE General 1995-1996 (Box 8)
  - Course Materials; CAS Grants Gifts and Awards (not including Ford):
    - Courses 1971-1975 (Box 9)
    - Courses 1980-1992 (Box 9)
    - Courses 1984-1985 (Box 9)
    - Intro to African Studies Proposal 1985 (Box 9)
    - Courses and Enrollments 1987-1988 (Box 9)
    - Course Enrollment 1988-1990 (Box 9)
    - African Studies Courses 1988-1989 (Box 9)
    - Course Seminar 1990 (Box 9)
    - Dialogues, Tutorials, and Peter's Seminars 1992 (Box 9)
    - Courses, Languages 1993-1994 (Box 9)
    - Course Certificates 1993 (Box 9)
    - Autumn, Winter, Spring Courses 1993-1994 (Box 9)
    - Summer Courses 1994 (Box 9)
    - Courses Summary 1994-1995 (Box 9)
    - Autumn, Winter, Spring Courses 1994-1995 (Box 9)
    - Courses and Degrees 1995 (Box 9)
    - Autumn, Winter, Spring Courses 1995-1996 (Box 9)
    - Time Grid Projected Courses 1995-1996 (Box 9)
    - Prism; Help Alpha Department 1995 (Box 9)
    - Summer Time Schedule 1995 (Box 9)
    - Course Seminar 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Autumn Courses 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Stanford Bulletin 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Time Schedules 1998-2000 (Box 9)
    - Courses 1998-1999 (Box 9)
    - Autumn, Winter, Spring Courses 1999-2000 (Box 9)
    - Autumn, Winter Courses 2000-2001 (Box 9)
    - Courses Bulletin 2004-2005 (Box 9)
    - Courses Handouts, Syllabi and Faculty Information:
      - Faculty 1971-1972 (Box 9)
      - African American Studies Courses 1971-1974 (Box 9)
      - Anthropology 1969-1976; Anthropology 1984-1988 (Box 9)
      - Communications 1973-1974 (Box 9)
      - Economics 1971-1974 (Box 9)
      - Food Research 1971-1972; Food Research 1988-1990 (Box 9)
      - History 1969-1978; History 1991-1995 (Box 9)
      - Linguistics 1969-1974; Linguistics: Swahili 1993-1994; Linguistics 1993-1994 (Box 9)
      - Political Science 1970-1975; Political Science 1988-1992 (Box 9)
      - Political Science 1991: African Identities Course Materials (Box 9)
      - Psychology 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - CAS Grants, Gifts and Awards (not including Ford Foundation):
      - Spencer Foundation Grant 1986 (Box 9)
      - Hewlett Grant Award 1988-1989 (Box 9)
      - Hewlett Requests/Awards 1990-1993 (Box 9)
      - Hewlett Grants 1992 (Box 9)
      - Hewlett Proposals 1993-1994 (Box 9)
      - Hewlett Faculty Grant 1993 (Box 9)
      - Montgomery Fund 1993 (Box 9)
      - Grant Proposal for the Improvement of Education 1994 (Box 9)
      - Stanford School of Education and CAS DOE Proposal 1994-1997 (Box 9)
      - Woodrow Wilson Grant 1996 (Box 9)
      - US AID-TELP 1997-1998 (Box 9)
  - Funding, Hausa Program, Receptions, Africa Table, Proposals, and Certificates:
    - Funding:
      - Sponsorship 1988 (Box 10)
      - Publication Funding 1992 (Box 10)
      - Funding Opportunities 1990-1994 (Box 10)
      - Funding Initiatives 1991-1992 (Box 10)
      - Award Letters from Donors (Hewlett, Montgomery) 1992-1993 (Box 10)
      - Boren Bill Funding Possible 1993 (Box 10)
      - Gift Processing 1993-1994 (Box 10)
      - Investor Responsibility Research Center 1994 (Box 10)
      - Funding Allocations 1994-1995 (Box 10)
      - Hewlett 1994-1996 (Box 10)
      - Bing Teaching Initiative 1995 (Box 10)
      - 2004-2005 Fundraising Initiatives (Box 10)
    - Hausa Program:
      - Intensive Summer Hausa Program Nigeria 1982 Preliminary Report (Box 10)
      - Proposal to Produce Hausa Textbook 1983 (Box 10)
      - Proposal for Intermediate Hausa Text 1983 (Box 10)
      - Visas 1984 (Box 10)
      - Hausa Textbook by Leben June 1984 (Box 10)
      - Group Projects Abroad – Intensive Hausa Institute – Summer 1984 (Box 10)
      - Travel Arrangements and Finances 1984 (Box 10)
      - Federal Funding for Hausa Program 1984 (Box 10)
      - Advanced Hausa Institute 1984 (Box 10)
      - Hausa Textbook Proposal 1984 (Box 10)
      - Students/Applicants Overseas Studies – Nigeria 84/85 (Box 10)
      - Levey, Hausa 1984 (Box 10)
      - Johnson, Brigham Summer 1984 (Box 10)
      - Davis, Anthony Summer 1984 (Box 10)
      - Cantrell, Brent 1984 (Box 10)
      - Bickmore, Lee 1984 (Box 10)
      - Hausa Program 1986 Proposal (Box 10)
      - Advances Hausa Institute Summer 1986 (Box 10)
    - Receptions:
      - Fall Reception 1963-1983 (Box 10)
      - Fall Reception 1987 (Box 10)
      - Fall Reception 1988 (Box 10)
      - Fall Reception 1989-1990 (Box 10)
      - Students and Address Lists Fall Reception 1990 (Box 10)
      - Fall Reception 1991 (Box 10)
      - Fall Reception 1992 (Box 10)
      - Autumn Reception 1993 (Box 10)
      - Autumn Reception 1994 (Box 10)
    - Africa Table:
      - Africa Table Events Calendar 1976 (Box 10)
      - "How To" File – Africa Table Newsletter 1986 (Box 10)
      - Africa Table 1988-1989 (Box 10)
      - Africa Table 1990-1992 (Box 10)
      - Oriki Theater September 1993 (Box 10)
      - Africa Table 1993-1995 (Box 10)
      - Africa Table News Clippings 1993-1994 (Box 10)
      - Africa Table 2000, 2001 (Box 10)
      - Darryl Prevost-Daffeh 1997-1998, Africa Table 1997-1998 (Box 10)
      - Africa Table Speakers, Bios, CVs, and Info 1987-1991, 1994-1996 (Box 10)
      - Africa Table Correspondence 1994-1995 (Box 10)
      - Africa Table Calendars/Fliers 1993-2002 (Box 10)
    - Proposals:
      - Proposals General 1987 (Box 10)
      - Proposals General 1990 (Box 10)
      - Refunding Application Proposal Joint Center 1991-1992 (Box 10)
      - 1993-1994 Continuation Grant Application Text (Box 10)
      - Info for Title XI Application 1993 (Box 10)
      - 1993 Proposal Half Page CVs (Box 10)
      - 1993 Proposal Cover Pages (Box 10)
      - Proposals General 1993-1994 (Box 10)
      - 1993 Proposal BAGEP (Box 10)
    - Certificates:
      - Certificate in African Studies Background and History 1990-1991 (Box 10)
      - Undergrad Outreach 1993 (Box 10)
      - Certificate Ordering 1994 (Box 10)
      - Certificate in African Studies 1995 (Box 10)
      - Wojcicki, Janet 1990-1991 (Box 10)
      - Crowell, Karen 1990-1991 (Box 10)
      - Arends, Amy 1991-1992 (Box 10)
      - Beaulier, Sharon 1991-1992 (Box 10)
      - Novy, Julia W. 1992-1993 (Box 10)
      - Perkins, Alexander 1992-1993 (Box 10)
      - Schwindt, Karin 1992-1993 (Box 10)
      - Stever, Maren 1992-1993 (Box 10)
      - Westley, Karen 1992-1993 (Box 10)
      - York, Dana 1992-1993 (Box 10)
      - Egan, Brian 1993-1994 (Box 10)
      - Farmer, Steven A. 1993-1994 (Box 10)
      - Keane, Julie M. 1993-1994 (Box 10)
      - Weeks, Dana 1993-1994 (Box 10)
      - Reilly Meaghan, 1993-1994 (Box 10)
      - Rhee, Michelle 1994-1995 (Box 10)
      - Tanaka, Nancy 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - Outreach, BAGEP, SPICE Nigeria Trip, SPICE:
    - Outreach:
      - "Mapping Africa" Curriculum Unit for Grades 6-10, by SPICE (Box 11)
      - Maggie's Educational Outreach Letter (Box 11)
      - Bay Area African Outreach (Box 11)
      - Stanford East African Relief Organization (Box 11)
      - South Africa Education Project (Box 11)
      - Outreach 1975-1982 (Box 11)
      - South Africa 1977-1978 (Box 11)
      - South Africa Education Project 1978-1982 (Box 11)
      - Teaching South Africa 1978 (Box 11)
      - Black Population Teaching Materials 1980 (Box 11)
      - "Green Revolution in Ivory Coast" by Sylvie Cohen, 1983 (Box 11)
      - Misc. Outreach 1983 (Box 11)
      - Gunn High School International Day 1984 (Box 11)
      - Ethnic Diversity 1984-1985 (Box 11)
      - South Africa Workshop Register 1986 (Box 11)
      - CISP 1986 (Box 11)
      - Report for Rockefeller Foundation 1990 (Box 11)
      - Links to African Universities, U. of Zimbabwe 1991 (Box 11)
      - Outreach Requests from Prisoners 1991 (Box 11)
      - Dear Education 1992 (Box 11)
      - Outreach Mini-Fellowships 1993 (Box 11)
      - Film Series Outreach 1992-1993 (Box 11)
      - Outreach Items 1993-1994 (Box 11)
      - African American Institute 1994 (Box 11)
      - AEGIS 1995 (Box 11)
      - ACCESS 1995 (Box 11)
    - BAGEP:
      - Global Consortium in the Bay Area 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - Intermediate Workshop BAGEP 1981 (Box 11)
      - BAGEP Summer Institute in Africa 1982 (Box 11)
      - BAGEP Resource Center Catalogue 1982 (Box 11)
      - BAGEP Training Institute Summer 1982 (Box 11)
      - BAGEP B 1983 (Box 11)
      - Summer Institute 1985 (Box 11)
      - BAGEP Team List 1985-1986 (Box 11)
      - BAGEP Workshop 1986 (Box 11)
      - BAGEP Resource Center Catalogue 1986-1987 (Box 11)
      - BAGEP 1993 (Box 11)
      - Teachers BAGEP 1993 (Box 11)
    - SPICE Nigeria Trip:
      - Nigeria Trip 1983 (Box 11)
      - Nigeria Trip Applications 1984 (Box 11)
      - Post-Trip (Box 11)
      - Orientations 1-6 1984 (Box 11)
      - Requests for Applications, Applicants, Selection Process, Letters of Acceptance and Rejection 1984 (Box 11)
      - Application, Letters, Mailing List 1984 (Box 11)
      - Pre-trip Contacts with Nigeria 1984 (Box 11)
      - Application, Selection Criteria Process, GPA Papers, pre-1984 (Box 11)
      - Thank-you Letters 1984 (Box 11)
    - SPICE:
      - BAGEP/SPICE 1980s (Box 11)
      - SPICE 1980-1982, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
      - Articles 1982 (Box 11)
      - SPICE 1984 (Box 11)
      - Receipts 1983-1986 (Box 11)
      - 1985 Curriculum Guidelines Summer Institute (Box 11)
      - Film and Video Collection 1986 (Box 11)
      - Lesson Content Checklist 1986 (Box 11)
      - Office Memos 1986-1987 (Box 11)
      - Staff Meetings 1986-1987 (Box 11)
      - Publications 1986-1987 (Box 11)
      - BAGEP/SPICE Misc. 1987 (Box 11)
      - Purchase Orders 1987 (Box 11)
      - Curriculum Materials Evaluation Checklist 1987 (Box 11)
      - SPICE Catalogue 1991-1993 (Box 11)
      - SPICE General 1993-1994 (Box 11)
      - Oakland/Ghana 1994 SPICE (Box 11)
      - SPICE 1995-1996 (Box 11)
  - Events, FORD, Institutes:
    - Events:
      - South Africa Forum (Box 12)
      - Africa Week (Box 12)
      - Events General 1983, 1984, 1986 (Box 12)
      - Crossroads Africa Oct. 14-15, 1987 (Box 12)
      - Speakers 1986-1987 (Box 12)
      - African Studies Faculty Seminar 1987-1990 (Box 12)
      - Chinua Achebe Feb. 1988 (Box 12)
      - "Africa Unadorned" Exhibit 1988 (Box 12)
      - Events/Activities 1988-1989 (Box 12)
      - Speakers 1988-1989 (Box 12)
      - Visitors 1989 (Box 12)
      - Events 1988-1989 (Box 12)
      - Lecturers 1990 (Box 12)
      - Events 1990-1991 (Box 12)
      - Rally Celebrating Mandela's Release 1990 (Box 12)
      - Peter Horn 1990 (Box 12)
      - Luncheon – Zimbabwean Minister of State for Scholarship Dec. 4, 1990 (Box 12)
      - Julie Frederikse, Nov. 29-30, 1990 (Box 12)
      - Odhiambo, Jan. 23-24, 1991 (Box 12)
      - Events 1992 (Box 12)
      - IIS Events and Fellowships 1992-1994 (Box 12)
      - N. Alexander Nov. 1993 (Box 12)
      - Events 1993, 1994-1995 (Box 12)
      - Symposium: Global Presence of African Spirit in Contemporary Art 1994 (Box 12)
      - Events 1996, 2001-2002 (Box 12)
    - Ford:
      - FORD RFP (Box 12)
      - FORD Summer (Box 12)
      - NWU Oct. 1995 (Box 12)
      - Proposal Drafts, Preliminary Emails 1995 (Box 12)
      - Announcement and Guidelines 1995 (Box 12)
      - Preliminary Notes 1995 (Box 12)
      - Collaborative Projects 1995 (Box 12)
      - Dean's Office 1995 (Box 12)
      - Diversity Table 1995 (Box 12)
      - Budget 1995 (Box 12)
      - Appendices 1995 (Box 12)
      - URO 1995 (Box 12)
      - FORD Foundation Funding 1995 (Box 12)
      - FORD Report: A Perspective on African Studies 1995 (Box 12)
      - FORD Foundation Proposal 1995-1996 (Box 12)
      - Expenditure Report 1995-1997 (Box 12)
      - Joint Center FORD Review and Final Report 1997 (Box 12)
      - FORD Grant Proposal 1997 Early Versions (Box 12)
      - FORD Grant 1997 Backup (Box 12)
      - FORD Grant Joint Center 1998 (Box 12)
      - FORD Summer Faculty Workshop, UC Berkeley, 2000 (Box 12)
      - FORD Grant Proposal 1999-2001 (Box 12)
    - Institutes:
      - SSRC Institute 1988-1989 (Box 12)
      - Summer Institute on Africa Correspondence 1982 (Box 12)
      - SCALI 1992 (Box 12)
      - Yale Summer Institute 1993 (Box 12)
      - Language Institute 1994 (Box 12)
      - SCALI 1994 Boston U. (Box 12)
      - Food Research Institute 1995-1996 (Box 12)
      - Summer Cooperative Language Institute Berkeley 1995 (Box 12)
      - Summer Cooperative Language Institute Ohio 1996 (Box 12)
      - Dolcini, Becky A. 1996 (Box 12)
      - Best, Dalila Victoria 1996 (Box 12)
      - Calzolai, Leola A. 1996 (Box 12)
      - Carpenter, Brenda L. 1996 (Box 12)
      - Dolan, Kevin 1996 (Box 12)
      - Dorsey, Aaron D. 1996 (Box 12)
      - Harper, Kerri N. 1996 (Box 12)
      - Flowers, Wesley 1996 (Box 12)
      - Hecker, Brigitte E. 1996 (Box 12)
      - Henderson, Taja-Nia 1996 (Box 12)
      - Ng, Genevieve Y. 1996 (Box 12)
      - Salavisa, Gisela L. 1996 (Box 12)
      - Washington, Henry 1996 (Box 12)
      - Williams, Rochelle 1996 (Box 12)
      - York, Peter A. 1996 (Box 12)
      - Summer Cooperative Language Institute 1997 (Box 12)
      - SCALI Summer 2002 (Box 12)
      - Joint Center 2001 Undergraduate Institute "South Africa, Contested Traditions" Readings Packet (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous by Year:
    - Africana Collection (Library) (Box 13)
    - African Program Hoover Institution 1977-1978 (Box 13)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 13)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 13)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 13)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 13)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 13)
    - 1985-1986:
      - Carol Williams (Photographer) 1985 (Box 13)
    - 1986-1987:
      - Appointment of Historian on South Africa 1987 (Box 13)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 13)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 13)
    - Katherine Welsh Chron. 1988-1990 (Box 13)
    - 1989-1990:
      - PCAA 1989 Directory (Box 13)
      - Internews US-South Africa Spacebridge 1989-1990 (Box 13)
      - URO African Research Grants 1989-1993 (Box 13)
      - Chain Letter Anti-Apartheid 1990 (Box 13)
    - 1990-1991:
      - Staff Search 1990-1992 (Box 13)
    - 1991-1992:
      - Will Leben/Language 1991-1992 (Box 13)
      - Nigeria Trip Proposal 1992 (Box 13)
    - 1992-1993:
      - Central State U., Wilberforce (1992, University Linkages) (Box 13)
      - Religions Exhibition 1993 (Box 13)
    - Amy Beihl Memorial Fund 1993 (Box 13)
    - NSEP Boren Bill 1994 (Box 13)
    - African Studies in the Humanities Center 1994-1996 (Box 13)
    - 1993-1994:
      - Meyer 1993-1994 (Box 13)
    - African Studies 3-Year Plan 1994-1997 (Box 13)
    - 1994-1995:
      - Dissertation Workshops 1995 (Box 13)
      - Area Studies Meetings 1994-1995 (Box 13)
      - NCSA 1994-1995 (Box 13)
      - Linguistics 1994-1995 (Box 13)
    - 1995-1996:
      - Stanford Program in International Legal Studies 1996 (Box 13)
      - Mudimbe Seminar 1996 (Box 13)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 13)
    - 1997-1998:
      - Mudimbe Humanitarianism 1998 (Box 13)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 13)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 13)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 13)
  - FLAS:
    - FLAS 1985-1988 (Box 14)
    - Federal Register/FLAS Reporting 1987-88, 1993-1997 (Box 14)
    - FLAS 1987 (Box 14)
    - FLAS Awards 1988-1989, Summer 1989 (Box 14)
    - FLAS Fellows 1990-1994 (Box 14)
    - Recommendations for Graduate Awards FLAS 1990-1991 (Box 14)
    - FLAS Letters to Committee 1990 (Box 14)
    - FLAS 1991-1992 (Box 14)
    - FLAS 1991 Meredith McKittrick (Box 14)
    - Draft FLAS Application 1992 (Box 14)
    - FLAS 1992 Barton Kilpatrick (Box 14)
    - Correspondence with US Department of Education (Box 14)
    - FLAS 1992-1993 (Box 14)
    - FLAS 1KEF 907 1992-1993 (Box 14)